This card came up very clearly.
It’s about connection,
partnership,
and two destinies intertwining.
Like two timelines crossing?
More like fate crossing.
It’s karma from a past life carrying over to the present.
I don’t believe in past lives.
I live in the present.
Even the present…
isn’t just a coincidence.
When the time comes, you’ll understand.
You and he
will shape the past, the present, and the future
together.
If you don’t confess,
we’ll whip you until you do!
I’m sorry I couldn’t help you.
Just treating my wounds is more than enough.
Why do I keep looking at you
whether you’re asleep or awake?
I hereby appoint you as Phra Sriprach.
If I wish to admire the lotus in your hand,
would you allow me?
It’s just a market.
Why do you look so happy?
Of course I am.
I don’t get out much.
I’m buried in cases every day.
You know, work and all.
I always stay in the same place,
and hardly see a place like this.
You seem so easy to please.
Just a change of scenery,
and you’re already beaming.
Maybe I don’t know you well enough.
From now on,
I want to get to know you better.
What do you think?
Good idea, P'Muen.
I want to get to know you too.
Let’s start with something simple.
Food.
What’s your favorite food?
Uh…
I love Som Tam.
Som Tam?
What is it?
Is it like the Tam Som I know?
Then is your Tam Som like the Som Tam I know?
Are you messing with me?
I’m kidding.
Som Tam is…
shredded green papaya pounded in a mortar,
then add palm sugar, chilies, fish sauce,
tomatoes, dried shrimp, and long beans,
and pound everything together.
This is making me hungry.
You mean Malacca?
Is it the fruit the Dutch brought here?
Malacca?
Papaya?
That’s right, P’Muen.
So, can your Tam Som beat my Som Tam?
But judging from the name Tam Som,
it sounds like a mess, not something tasty.
Tam Som is made with sour fruits,
like madan, tamarind, or bilimbi,
and pound them in a mortar.
Then add fish sauce and dried chilies,
and keep pounding it all together.
It tastes amazing.
I’m hungry already.
Gaew!
Oh, hello, Falcon.
I have something to tell you.
Lord Muen.
May I speak with Gaew alone for a moment?
Of course. He won’t mind.
Go ahead.
Maria and I are officially together now.
That's amazing!
Congratulations. You finally did it.
Keep it a secret for now.
Why?
Maria’s father, Fanik,
doesn’t like that I’m from a different faith
and thinks I’m not worthy of his only daughter.
So Maria and I can’t make our relationship public
until her father accepts us.
Don’t worry, my lord.
You’ll finally be together.
See you around.
Gaew.
What were you talking about?
Why did you have to stand so close and hold hands?
Huh?
It’s nothing important. Let’s go.
Hey.
If it’s not important,
then why did you whisper?
He just doesn't want anyone else to know.
It’s a secret.
A secret so big…
that you can’t even tell me?
Okay, I’ll tell you.
But you can’t tell anyone.
Falcon and Mali are going to be together.
How could they be together?
P’Muen!
It’s a secret.
Her father doesn’t approve.
How could that happen?
They’ll make it work. Trust me.
Why are you so sure?
You wouldn’t believe me anyway.
I won't say anything.
I’m going to see Mali.
P’Yam.
Yes, sir.
If you use lady finger bananas, it’ll taste sweeter.
Fry them until they’re crispy,
then take them out and let the oil drain.
Alright.
Mali.
Falcon just told me.
Congratulations.
But…
I know.
That’s why I want to cheer you up.
Your father may not accept your relationship now,
but one day,
he’ll accept it and let you two get married.
I hope you’re right.
Are you in a hurry?
No. Why?
I’m teaching her how to make Pisang Goreng.
I wanted you to try some.
Pisang goreng?
What’s that? I’ve never heard of it.
It’s fried bananas.
I’m teaching her a recipe from the foreigners.
You coat the bananas in batter, then fry them until they’re crispy,
and let the oil drain.
Can I try one?
I want to see if it tastes like the ones back home.
Of course.
Hm.
So good.
But the name’s a little too hard.
How about this?
Since you got the idea from the foreigners,
why don’t we call it Kluay Khaek?
It’s short and easy to remember.
Kluay Khaek?
You know, besides bananas, you can fry other things too.
Like sweet potatoes, taro, pumpkin,
and even pineapple.
Pineapple?
Yeah.
If you add some coconut and sprinkle a little sesame,
it’ll be really delicious.
Isn’t that strange,
my lord?
Lately, Lord Gaew has been interested in cooking,
not sword fighting like before.
This Gaew doesn’t seem like the old Gaew.
Hey.
What is it, P'Muen?
Let me see your swordsmanship.
Sure.
Grip.
Lower.
Close, lift, slash, thrust.
Close, lift, dance.
Well, speechless, aren't you?
I just want to spar with you.
What kind of stance is that?
So strange.
Come on, P’Muen.
This is how I was taught.
Stop fooling around.
Fight me.
Alright.
Get ready!
Come on.
Hey!
You’re serious?
That hurts.
You lost because of those weird moves.
In swordsmanship,
I am no match for you.
But in horsemanship,
you will surely lose to me.
You can ride a horse?
Want to find out?
Are you challenging me?
Are you sure you want to race me?
Absolutely.
Is this my horse?
Have you lost your mind?
That’s P’Sri’s horse.
You’ve never had a horse.
Can you handle it?
Just wait and see.
Are you ready?
Hey, that's cheating! Fine, bring it on!
What do you think? Am I amazing?
Take the horses back.
Gaew.
Who are you?
Did losing make you lose your mind too?
I’m Gaew, your younger brother.
No.
You’re not my younger brother.
I…
Dech. Gaew.
Oh, Wad.
What brings you here?
Nothing.
I just wanted to practice riding too.
How did you know we were here?
The servants told me you were at the stables,
so I followed you.
I brought him here to test his riding skills
because he said no one could match him.
Yes, sir.
Gaew?
Really?
Yeah.
I even beat P’Muen just now.
Next time, I won’t lose.
That sounds like fun.
Mind if I join in?
Sure.
No, I mean…
I want to race against Gaew instead of you.
Is that alright, Gaew?
No problem.
No problem?
What is it?
It means I’m fine with that.
Let's let the horses drink some water first.
Sounds good.
Then I'll go water my horse too.
Go ahead.
Are you ready?
Gaew.
I've been ready.
Hold on.
Since I'm not racing,
can my horse participate in my place?
Wait.
Gaew's horse looks much faster.
If he switch horses, he might not be used to it,
and end up losing to me.
This isn't my horse.
It belongs to P'Sri.
Besides,
no matter which horse I ride, I'll still win.
Bring it over.
Take good care of Gaew, buddy.
Go!
My lord.
Bring me the horse.
Go!
Ah!
My lord!
Stop!
Don't touch him.
P’Pin, bring me two wooden boards.
Let’s take him home.
Yes, sir.
Easy now, P'Muen.
Dech, I'm sorry. I didn't mean to.
P'Pin, P'Yam.
Wait outside. I'll take care of him.
Yes, sir.
Go.
How are you feeling, P'Muen?
It hurts a lot.
-Easy now.
-What are you doing?
Easy.
Ow!
What are you doing? It hurts!
Ready?
One, two.
Hey, that really hurts.
How does it feel now?
It still hurts.
What are you doing?
One, two.
How about now?
Better.
But still hurts.
Easy.
Keep your elbow bent.
Your bone is back in place,
but it still hurts because the muscles are inflamed.
I'll make you a sling,
so your shoulder won’t pop out again.
Keep it like this.
Don't move your arm.
If you don't listen,
and it dislocates again,
I might not be able to fix it.
If you need to bathe,
ask P'Pin to help you.
Or if he can't, I'll do it.
How do you...
know so much about this?
I told you I'm a doctor.
Get some rest.
Gaew.
Thank you for taking good care of me.
You're welcome.
My lord.
What is it?
I have something to tell you about Lord Muen’s accident.
Is something wrong?
Nothing.
Go!
Ah!
My lord!
Don't touch him.
Wad.
Let’s go to the sword school.
I came to return this to you.
It isn’t mine.
Maybe someone dropped it near the stables.
I hadn’t even mentioned the stables.
Was it you who put a nail under my saddle,
and got P’Muen hurt?
Wad would never hurt Dech.
Why would he do that?
Yeah, Wad.
Tell me.
Why did you do it?
How P’Muen would feel if he found out...
his friend did this?
I never meant for Dech to get hurt.
So it’s me you were trying to hurt?
Yes.
I wanted to teach you a lesson.
What lesson?
What’s your problem, Wad?
You’ve gone too far.
What if P’Muen had broken an arm?
I’m sorry Dech got caught in the middle.
I wish it was you instead.
Gaew.
You’re not a real man!
Stop it!
That’s enough, Wad. Gaew.
P’Yam, let go.
Wad.
Wait.
Where are you going?
Rueng.
Did you come to gloat over Dech’s accident too?
No.
Wait.
Where are you going?
Home.
I’ll walk you home.
It’s okay, I can get home on my own.
But I want to.
Suit yourself.
Tia.
Yes.
Are you done?
Yes, Your Majesty.
Let Sri read it.
Yes.
Here you go, Sri.
Read this poem.
Go on.
Why are you so quiet?
You wrote this poem, didn’t you?
I could tell at a glance it was yours.
Did you drop it?
Yes.
A graceful beauty, so soft and fair,
So delicate beyond compare.
All who behold you stand in awe,
captivated by your irresistible allure.
This poem is so beautiful.
Don’t you think so, Thao-Srichulaluck?
Yes.
Sriprach.
You are truly a brilliant poet.
See?
Your poetry is dangerously enchanting,
stealing the hearts of countless women.
Even now,
Jam, my consort, is pleased with it.
Sri.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your poem is exquisite, Sri.
Thank you, Your Majesty. It is my greatest honor.
My thoughts are bound to your noble grace.
While I grieve in my lowly place.
Of all the souls to love,
I fall for one forbidden.
I am but dust beneath your feet,
unworthy of
heaven above.
Sri, you fool.
His Majesty has only shown you love and kindness.
How could you even think of betraying him?
P’Sri.
I heard that
you’re about to be promoted to Lord Phra Sriprach.
So…
Congratulations.
But do you mind if I say something?
When you become Sriprach,
I hope you’ll think carefully
about who you choose to love.
Don’t fall for someone
who already belongs to another
or is already married.
I just want to warn you.
Lord Phra Sriprach has arrived.
I must have been blind.
Otherwise, I would’ve known that
the man standing before me
is the kingdom’s greatest poet
and His Majesty’s favorite.
Please forgive me.
Last time, I didn’t know my place
and dared to speak with Thao-Srichulaluck,
His Majesty’s royal consort.
We didn’t know each other.
What happened back then
wasn’t anyone’s fault.
But this time,
we both know
that our duty is to remain loyal
and faithful to the king.
Isn’t that right?
Yes.
Hurry back to serve His Majesty.
Please allow me to take my leave.
This is for you.
Go back and take care of your mother’s funeral, P’Yam.
Take it.
And don’t worry about me.
I can take care of myself.
Yes, sir.
Are you going alone?
Why don’t you take P’Pin with you?
I did,
but I don’t know if Lord Muen will allow it.
No.
Pin.
If you’re not here,
who’s going to grind my ink
and help me bathe?
Pee and poop too.
How am I supposed to do that?
But I…
Am I not making myself clear?
Loud and clear, sir.
You’re so mean.
Is that all?
I’ll help you myself.
Okay.
What does “okay” mean?
It means “agreed.”
Thank you, my lord.
Hurry up. Yam must be waiting for you.
-Yes, sir.
-Go.
You’re acting all cool.
Ow.
Ow, Pin!
Pin!
What do you want?
I want to grind the ink.
Can you help me?
What are you looking at?
Do I have ink on my face?
No.
I wasn’t looking.
It’s done.
Can you hand me the quill?
The quill?
There.
Please.
Quill?
Come on.
I’ll help you.
Where do I write?
The second line.
You can use that hand?
Ow!
This side hurts too.
Come here.
Are you coming with me?
Yeah.
I don’t want you to be alone.
Thanks for coming with me.
I’ve packed some cooked rice and dried fish.
We can eat on the way.
Let’s go.
Come on.
Gaew.
Yes?
Help me take off my shirt.
I want to take a bath.
How’s your arm?
Much better.
Gaew.
Go take a bath.
I wish I could bathe with you like this
every day.
You can.
Overall, his condition is stable.
His blood pressure and pulse are normal.
But we still can’t determine
why he hasn’t regained consciousness.
It may be
acute shock.
Thank you very much.
Thank you, doctor.
Rich, you have to help him.
No matter what’s wrong with Great,
or how hard it is.
Please do your best to help him.
Even if I have to sell my resort,
I’ll do it.
Yes, Grandma.
What’s gotten into you two?
One’s heart is burning with love,
while the other’s hiding it deeply.
Maybe Lord Sriprach
has fallen for someone who’s already taken.
Politics won’t be your downfall,
but love will.
You’ve fallen for someone, haven’t you?
Do you really want to know?
Then, go look into a looking glass,
and you shall find the answer.